Guide to the Hana Ginzbarg Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Hana Ginzbarg Papers
1962-1991
1970-1985
2010-014
Ginzbarg, Hana
9.50 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Materials in this collection represent Hana Ginzbarg’s working files for Armand Bayou.
Biographical Information:
Starting in 1970, Hana Ginzbarg spearheaded the campaign to rename and preserve Middle Bayou. Renamed became Armand Bayou to memorialize Armand Yramategui, a conservationist beloved by Houston’s environmental community. Ginzbarg devoted herself to the campaign to preserve Armand Bayou as “a small urban wilderness reserve” and protect it from impending residential development. Ginzbarg sent letters, made phone calls, photographed the bayou, attended political meetings, wrote press releases and newsletter columns, and generally performed like a whirling dervish for whom no task was too insignificant to merit her careful attention. It should be noted that Ginzbarg became acquainted with the bayou systems in Houston through her participation in the “Save Buffalo Bayou” campaign mounted by the Bayou Preservation Association in whose records also are preserved in the Houston History Archives.
As preserved by the campaign, Armand Bayou Nature Center includes 500 acres of the natural wetlands forest, prairie, and marsh habitats once abundant in the Houston/Galveston area. It offers habitat for 370 species of birds, mammals, reptiles and amphibians, and offers hiking trails, exhibits, field trips, Scout programs, birding, and a farm, and it an effective natural flood management system. Money, land, and development were the triggers in the Armand Bayou preservation campaign, rather than local government action.
Sources:
Tomkins-Walsh, T. L., “’To Combine Many and Varied Forces:’ The Hope of Houston’s Environmental Activism, 1923-1999.” In Martin V. Melosi and Joseph A. Pratt, Energy Metropolis: An Environmental History of Houston and the Gulf Coast. University of Pittsburgh Press, 2007, 241-259
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Leaflets (printed works); Letters (correspondence); Minutes; Newsletters; Publications (document genre); Reports
Topical Term:
Environmental education; Green movement; Issues in environmental politics; Local government and environmental policy; Urban parks; Wilderness areas
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
Bayou Preservation Association (BPA)(http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=376)
Citizens’ Environmental Coalition (CEC) (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=240)
The Park People (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=225)
Scope and Contents
Materials in this collection represent Hana Ginzbarg’s working files for Armand Bayou. To make the files accessible to the public, they were organized into three series. Series 1 includes materials related to Ginzbarg’s initial campaign to prevent development in the Armand Bayou area. Papers in Series 2 cover the subsequent efforts to preserve Armand Bayou as a nature education center and protect the area from proposed encroachments. Papers in Series 3 include maps and oversized documents.
It should be noted that this collection represents only a portion of Hana Ginzbarg’s papers. She retains her papers related to other campaigns and issues, particularly regarding her exhaustive work on the Bellaire Nature Discovery Center. More of Ginzbarg’s papers will come to the Houston History Archives at a later date.
Detailed List of Contents
- Armand Bayou Preservation Campaign
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 incorporates documents related to the history behind the preservation campaign, including Yramategui’s death, the plans to develop residential housing in the Armand Bayou floodplain, plus the technical and economic reports on Armand Bayou. Campaign activities are represented in full detail.
  - Campaign History and Mission
    - Armand Bayou History Notes and Chronology, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Armand Bayou Acquisition, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Frank Kokesh Renaming Middle Bayou to Armand Bayou, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Notes and Media Regarding the History of Armand Bayou, 1970-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Notes and Summary Articles on Armand Bayou’s History, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Armand Yramategui, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Armand Bayou Park Dedication, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Publication on Hana Ginzbarg, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Armand Bayou Nature Center Incorporation, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Armand Bayou Acquisition, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ten Year Memorial for Armand Yramategui, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - James Herzberg- Preserving Armand Bayou, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Armand Bayou History and Chronology, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Interim Report on Upper Middle Bayou, Nov 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Army Corps of Engineers Flood Plan Study of Armand Bayou, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Armand Bayou Progress Report, January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Armand Bayou Status Report, January 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Armand Bayou Committee Report, December 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - City of Pasadena Drainage Study-Armand Bayou (1), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - City of Pasadena Drainage Study-Armand Bayou (2), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Armand Bayou Progress Report, January 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Armand Bayou Status Report, April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Friendswood Development Plans for Armand Bayou, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Proposals on the Armand Bayou Preservation and Recreation Area Key to Map, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Map of Clear Lake City, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - The 1971 Annual Report of the Advertising Council (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Various Maps of Armand Bayou and Vicinity, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Contract Between Housing and Urban Development and The City of Pasadena, June 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - City of Pasadena Ordinance to Purchase Part of Armand Bayou, Dec 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Priority Purchase Plan for the Park on Armand Bayou, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - HUD Application of the City of Pasadena for Open Space Land Acquisition Grant, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Parks and Wildlife Department and the Bureau of Outdoor Recreation, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Appeals to the Harris County Commissioners Court for Funding, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Outlined Plan for Armand Bayou by Hubert Davis, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - City of Pasadena vs. Taylor Lake Village Annexation, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Armand Bayou Park Planning and Review Subcommittee, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Harris County Former Boys Home Site, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Deed Restrictions Tract 7, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Armand Bayou Surveys, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Armand Bayou Acquisition Controversy-Tract 7, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Maps (1), undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Maps (2), undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Preservation Campaign Correspondence
    - Armand Bayou, January-June 1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Armand Bayou, July-December 1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Armand Bayou, January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Armand Bayou, February 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Armand Bayou, March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Armand Bayou, April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Armand Bayou, May 1971 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Armand Bayou, June 1971 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Armand Bayou, July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Armand Bayou, August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Armand Bayou, September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Armand Bayou, October 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Armand Bayou, November 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Armand Bayou, December 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Legacy of Parks (1), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Legacy of Parks (2), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Legacy of Parks (3), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Legacy of Parks (4), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Letters Regarding The Nature Conservancy and Armand Bayou, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bureau of Recreation, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Land Acquisition and Dredging Armand Bayou, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Mayor Clyde Doyle of Pasadena, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. S.M. Masha, Jr., 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Armand Bayou, January 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Armand Bayou, February 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Armand Bayou, March 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Armand Bayou, April 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Armand Bayou, May 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Armand Bayou, June 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Armand Bayou, July 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Armand Bayou, August 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Armand Bayou, September 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Armand Bayou, October 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Armand Bayou, November 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Armand Bayou, December 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - HUD Grant and Park Dedication Ceremony, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence with the State Legislature, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Hana Ginzbarg Speaking Engagements, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Armand Bayou, January 1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Armand Bayou, February 1973 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Armand Bayou, March 1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Armand Bayou, April 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Armand Bayou, May 1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Armand Bayou, June 1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Armand Bayou, July-September 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Armand Bayou, October-December 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Congratulations Letters Regarding New York Times Article on Armand Bayou, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters Regarding Reports on the Planning of Armand Bayou Park, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters of Appreciation for Armand Bayou Preservation Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife Commission Funding for Armand Bayou, Jan-June 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife Commission Funding for Armand Bayou, July-Dec 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Preservation Campaign Committee
    - “Armand Bayou Regional Park”, December 3, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Flood Drainage, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hiking Along Armand Bayou, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Preservation Committee -Statement by Hana N. Ginzbarg, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Legacy of Parks Program Funding Difficulties (1), 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Legacy of Parks Program Funding Difficulties (2), 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Clear Creek Basin Authority Resolution, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Clear Lake City Civic League Resolution, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Armand Bayou- Petition, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - City of Pasadena, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - “Hoped for” Park on Armand Bayou Petition and Mailer, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Housing and Urban Development Regulations on Open Space, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Inquiries, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Statement by Hana N. Ginzbarg, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Texas Governor Preston Smith’s Visit to Armand Bayou, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - City of Pasadena Resolution No. 72 Regarding Armand Bayou, February 1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - City of LaPorte Resolution No.72-01 Supporting the City of Pasadena and Armand Bayou Preservation, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Discover Armand Bayou Day City of Pasadena and HEP, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - ABC News Television Special Oceans: The Silent Crisis, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - HUD Final Environmental Statement Armand Bayou Park Land Acquisition Project, June 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Preservation of Armand Bayou Committee, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Statement by Hana N. Ginzbarg, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Press Releases, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Armand Bayou and Education, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Suggested Editorials, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Estuary Preservation Grants, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Houston Audubon Society Sponsored Nature Hikes, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Armand Bayou Fault Lines, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hana Ginzbarg Statement Before the Harris County Commissioners Court, January 1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Newsletter “Save Armand Bayou”, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Armand Bayou, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Harris County Citizens Form for Proposal of Armand Bayou Park, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Brochure Designers, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - “Armand Bayou Park in Jeopardy”, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife Commission Funding for Armand Bayou, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - County and Bureau of Recreation Ceremony, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Armand Bayou Regional Park Check-Passing Ceremony, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Preservation Campaign Fundraising
    - Armand Bayou Fund, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Armand Bayou Fundraising, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - A Grant Application, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Foundation Lists and Donations, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Letters to Foundations, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Fundraising Letters Regarding Environmental Studies, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Fundraising Letters from Allied Organizations and Related Agencies, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Grant Application to the Moody Foundation, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Fund Drive, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Environmental and Political Issues
    - Armand Bayou Land Subsidence Studies, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Armand Bayou Land Subsidence Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Armand Bayou Subsidence Maps, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Clippings-Land Subsidence, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Clippings-Land Subsidence, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Clippings-Land Subsidence, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Trends in Conservation and Land Use for the Soil Conservation Society of America, August 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife Brochures, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Political Mailer to the Taxpayers of the Clear Lake City Water Districts, January 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Nature Conservancy, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Pamphlet About the Woodlands First Phase, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - HUD Federal Insurance Administration, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Advocate Organizations
    - List of Organizations Involved with Armand Bayou Project, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Bayou Preservation Association (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Citizens Environmental Coalition (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Citizens Who Care (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Earth I Care (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Help Eliminate Pollution (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Houston Audubon Society (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - National Recreation and Park Association (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Outdoor Nature Club (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Rice Design Alliance (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Sierra Club Lone Star Chapter (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The Texas System of Natural Laboratories, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Interested Agencies
    - Harris County Flood Control District Policy and Criteria, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Department of Interior (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Clear Lake City Authority (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Preservation Campaign Publicity
    - Clippings, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Clippings Yramatagui’s Death, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Clippings, January 1971-June 1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Clippings, July 1971-December 1971 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Clippings, January 1972-March 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Clippings, April 1972-June 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Clippings, July 1972-September 1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Clippings, October 1972-December 1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Clippings, January 1973-March 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Clippings, April 1973-June 1973 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Clippings, July 1973-December 1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Articles Regarding the Naturalist Robert Vines, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of Appreciation to Hana Ginzbarg Deer Park Jaycees, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife and Armand Bayou, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and Notes Regarding the Texas State Legislature, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Time Magazine, Nov 13, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Houston Symphony Orchestra Pamphlet with Armand Bayou Advertisement, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Big Handbook, Bayou Interpretive Guide by the League of Women Voters, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Texas Society of Architects Award for Armand Bayou, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Clippings Texas Parks and Wildlife Commission Funding for Armand Bayou, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Articles and Letters Regarding Armand Yramatagui, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Other Various Publications, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Notes and Information
    - Notes (1) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Notes (2) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Armand Bayou Nature Center
  Series 2 contains the records of the early days of the Nature Center as an established non-profit entity, including board meetings, financial records, educational programs, and publicity.
  - Nature Center History and Mission
    - Armand Bayou By-laws, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Armand Bayou Acquisition, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Armand Bayou By-Laws, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Armand Bayou Items Requiring Early Action, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nature Center Board of Trustees
    - Report-Preliminary Report of the Houston Archeological Society, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Original List of Candidates for Trustees, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Major Responsibilities of the Board of Trustees (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Secretarial Procedures for Board Meetings, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Board of Trustees List, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Armand Bayou Annual Report, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Armand Bayou Nature Center Fact Sheet, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Executive Committee Agenda and Election Proxy, April 1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Director’s Report, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Report on the State of the Nature Center, May 1991 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Armand Bayou Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Nature Center Administration (Financial)
    - Armand Bayou Financial Statements, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Budget Interim, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Federal Outlays, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Armand Bayou Financials, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Audit Report, June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Armand Bayou Financials, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Financials, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Budget Statement, January-December 1981 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Financials, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Financials, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Nature Center Administration (Personnel)
    - Director Job Description, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Director Search, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Personnel Issues, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Personnel Policies, March 1982 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Staff Issues and Concerns, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Organizational Chart and Personnel Policies, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Personnel Issues, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Nature Center Planning and Hana Ginzbarg’s Role, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Nature Center Fundraising
    - Donations of Materials and Services, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Challenge Grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Native Plant Drive and Annual Fund Drive, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Merry Christmas from the Armand Bayou Creatures, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Nature Center Correspondence
    - Armand Bayou, January-February 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Armand Bayou, March-April 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Armand Bayou, May-June 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Armand Bayou, July-August 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Armand Bayou, September-October 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Armand Bayou, November-December 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Armand Bayou, January-February 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Armand Bayou, March-April 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Armand Bayou, May-June 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Armand Bayou, July-December 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Armand Bayou-Hana Ginzbarg’s Correspondence from Holland, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Armand Bayou, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Armand Bayou, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Armand Bayou, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Armand Bayou, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Armand Bayou, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Armand Bayou, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Armand Bayou, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Armand Bayou, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Armand Bayou, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Armand Bayou, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Armand Bayou, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Armand Bayou, January –March 1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Armand Bayou, April-June 1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Armand Bayou, July-December 1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Armand Bayou, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Texas Park Recreation and Open Space Bill, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - FM 2351 Controversy, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - National Park Service, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Nature Center Educational Programs
    - Trail Guides and the Natural History of Armand Bayou, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Bayou Interpretive Guide Workshops and Volunteers, 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Trail Development, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Summer Programs, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Step Program, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Hana G. Boat Acquisition and Use, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Nature Center Tours and Trails, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Summer Program and Anthropology Courses, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Programs of Armand Bayou Nature Center, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - A Comparison of Traditional and Computer Assisted Pre-Instructional Materials for Science Learning, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Bayou Interpretive Guide Tour Report, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Nature Center Planning and Protection
    - Archeological Investigations Along Armand Bayou, Department of Anthropology Rice University and The Houston Anthropological Society, September 1974 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Master Drainage Study of Armand Bayou, March 1979 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Master Drainage Study of Armand Bayou Chapter 6, March 1979 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Master Drainage Study of Armand Bayou Appendix A, March 1979 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Controlling Urban Runoff: A Practical Manual for Planning and Designing Urban BMPs, July 1987 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Texas Water Commission, Baywood Country Club, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Greater Houston Area Water Quality Management Plan, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Extension of FM 2351 (1) Controversy, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 48)